Hans Hofmann
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Estate of Hans Hofmann, 1945-1974, undated, Series 9:; (Box 19; 0.5 linear ft.; Reel 5811)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1974, 9.3:
    - Estate of Hans Hofmann v. Alarms & Communications Corporation, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Gift of Household Items and Art Supplies to Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, Inc., 1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Probate Decree and Related Correspondence, 1966, 1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Purchase of Jacques Camins Film of Hofmann with Class in Provincetown, 1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Purchase of Warren, Conn., Property, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Theft of Paintings, 1966 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Wills and Related Correspondence, 1966 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
- Papers of Renate Schmitz Hofmann, 1962-1967, undated, Series 10:; (Box 19; 6 folders; Reel 5811)
  German-born Renate Schmitz Hofmann (1930-1992) inspired Hofmann's Renate series painted in 1965, the year they were married. Her papers include condolence letters and records regarding Hans Hofmann's funeral. Among her other correspondence are a letter addressed to Dave about her relationship with Hofmann, a copy of a letter from John Querido to Samuel Kootz concerning the accusation that Renate had allowed other dealers to sell paintings from the Hofmann Estate, and correspondence with Henry Ford II and the Ford Motor company regarding complaints about their vehicle. A file titled Art Theft contains clippings about the theft of paintings from Hofmann's Provincetown home and their subsequent recovery. Notes consist of a spiral notebook, mostly in shorthand, containing what are probably notes from Nina Morgan's courses "Art of Conversation" and "Creative Living" held at Central YWCA; also, loose notes, "History of Western Philosophy."
  Postcards from Renate Schmitz to Hofmann are filed with Correspondence (Series 1), and Photographs (Series 6) include pictures of her. Additional records regarding the art theft from the Provincetown house are included with the Hans Hofmann Estate Records (Series 9).
  - Notes, 1962, undated (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1967, undated (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Condolence Letters, A-Z, 1966 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Funeral of Hans Hofmann, 1966 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Art Theft, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Business Cards, Address Notes, undated (Box 19, Reel 5811)